let's look at the answer for our cache
line size quiz we are asked to determine
which of these are not good line sizes
for a two kilobyte cache a one byte line
is not a good one because it doesn't
exploit spatial locality and because
word size accesses we'll need to access
multiple blocks or multiple lines in the
cache so this is definitely not a good
size 32 bytes is a good size it exploits
spatial locality it's not too large and
it's a power of two so we can easily
locate blocks if I give you an address
you can easily find what block does it
belong to 48 bytes is a good size as far
as it's not too large or too small but
it's not a power of two so if we are
given an address and we need to find out
what is the block that contains that
address we need to divide by 48 which is
much more complicated than dividing by a
power of two for example for a 32 byte
size the lowest five bits of the address
tell us where we are within the block
this is kind of telling us where within
the 32 bytes of the block we are and the
upper bits of the address basically are
the block number so we divide by 32
simply by discarding the lowermost
32 bytes in contrast dividing by 48
bytes would actually need to be a
division by 48 so this is not a good
line size 64 bytes is also a reasonable
blocks as it's larger than 32 but still
a lot of them fit in a two kilobyte
cache one kilobyte is good because it's
a power of two but only two of them fit
in a two kilobyte cache so this is not a
good line size because it is too large
given that the cache is only two
kilobytes in size what we want to have
as a block size is something that is a
power of two exploits spatial locality
but still a significant number of them
fit in our cache